Gianluca

Senior Full Stack Developer

Summary

Gianluca is passionate about full-stack development, REST architecture and Agile methodology, and JavaScript as his primary programming language. Gianluca has been working with IT for more than 12 years, and he has 9 years of experience. Gianluca specializes in JavaScript, using SPA frameworks like AngularJS, Angular, React, and Node.js for back-end development. Now Gianluca is going to work in upwork.

Skills

Languages

TypeScript, CSS, JavaScript, GraphQL, HTML, HTML5, ECMAScript (ES6), SQL, C#, PHP, Java, C#.NET

- Frontend
 - React, Next, Vue, Nuxt, GraphQL, Angular
- Backend
 - Java, Springboot, Node, Express, PHP, Laravel, C#, ASP.NET, MsSql, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB, Oracle, Mongodb, Firestore, Redis
- **Secondary Skills**: Git, CI/CD, Docker, Jenkins, SAAS, Serverless/lambda, AWS, GCP, Azure, Microservice, Stripe, Twilio, Zoom, Auth0, Okta

Work Experience

Senior Full Stack Developer Norstella

2022.3 - 2024.6

Morrisville Pennsylvania, United States

- Configured Terraform from scratch for the monorepo project that serves several front ends at once.
- Planned and architected a process to convert several front ends into a single repository following monorepo standards with Nx and Next.js.
- Developed a conversion tool to migrate Contentful apps into KeystoneJS CMS.
- Designed and implemented a CI/CD pipeline to cover the monorepo approach, saving time not to redeploy non-affected projects.

Senior Full-stack Node.js Developer Shrader Group

2019.5-2022.2

Conshohocken Pennsylvania, United States

- Developed the back-end architecture from the top using Node.js as the main technology.
- Architected and implemented the application inside the AWS environment.
- Created a task scheduler that handles time-zones issues among global users to ensure that the clients receive their tasks at the correct time period.
- Integrated several social logins such as Facebook and Instagram.
- Integrated financial banking into the back end following security patterns.
- Maintained and created new features in their back end.
- Acted as a lead back-end software engineer and supported and maintained the AWS environment that held EKS, SES, and RDS, to name a few.
- Integrated external communication services such as SendGrid and Twilio.
- Supporting the growth of 0 to 7,500+ users during the initial to the end phase of the contract.

Full-stack Engineer | Node.js/React Developer Yara International

2016.1 - 2019.5

Oslo, Norway

- Worked with an enterprise company via Toptal and developed an internal application from scratch using React, NestJS, and GraphQL.
- Integrated the offered design pages and made them responsive on mobile, tablet, and desktop.
- Created the OAuth flow using Auth0 as an external provider.
- Extracted huge data information stored in the client's AWS S3 bucket.
- Created a back-end server using NestJS and GraphQL with Relay.
- Used the company design framework made with styled-components and created custom styled-components to match with the project requirements.

Education

Bachelor's Degree in Information Systems

Federal University of Technology - Parana, Brazil